Guide to the Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr. papers, 1922-2007
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- Series I: Correspondence, 1923-2007; 384760; 286 boxes
  - Subseries I.A. Alphabetical correspondence, 1934-2006; 384761; 150 boxes
    - Tree, Marietta, 1953-2002; 385328 (Box 133, Folder 1-6)
    - Tree, Marietta, 1953-2002; 385329 (Box 134, Folder 1)
    - Tru-Ty, 385330 (Box 134, Folder 2)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1951; 385331 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Ts-Tz, 385332 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Tu-Ty, 385333 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 1976-1994; 385334 (Box 135, Folder 1-4)
    - Twentieth Century Fund, 1976-1994; 385335 (Box 136, Folder 1-3)
    - U, 385336 (Box 136, Folder 4-5)
    - U, 385337 (Box 137, Folder 1-2)
    - Udall, Stewart, 1997-1998; 385338 (Box 137, Folder 3)
    - Updike, John, 2002; 385339 (Box 137, Folder 4)
    - V, 385340 (Box 137, Folder 5-8)
    - Va-Vu, 385341 (Box 138, Folder 1)
    - Val-Ver, 385342 (Box 138, Folder 2)
    - Valenti, Jack, 2006; 385343 (Box 138, Folder 3)
    - Vanden Heuvel, William J., 1967-1994; 385344 (Box 138, Folder 4)
    - Vi-Viz, 385345 (Box 138, Folder 5)
    - Villard, Donald, 1941; 385346 (Box 138, Folder 6)
    - Volman, Sacha, 1968-1993; 385347 (Box 139, Folder 1-2)
    - W, 385348 (Box 139, Folder 3-5)
    - W-Wh, 385349 (Box 140, Folder 1)
    - W.W. Norton and Co., 1990-1999; 385350 (Box 140, Folder 2)
    - Wa, 385351 (Box 140, Folder 3)
    - Wa-Wan, 385352 (Box 140, Folder 4)
    - Wa-Wat, 385353 (Box 141, Folder 1)
    - Wade, Richard C., 1966-1994; 385354 (Box 141, Folder 2-3)
    - Wallace, Mike, 2002; 385355 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - War-Wee, 385356 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Waters, Maxine, 1998-1999; 385357 (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - We-Wel, 385358 (Box 142, Folder 1)
    - Wea-Wer, 385359 (Box 142, Folder 2)
    - Wechsler, James A., 1949-1994; 385360 (Box 142, Folder 3)
    - Wechsler, James A., 1949-1994; 385361 (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - Weh-Wer, 385362 (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - Welles, Harriette (Mrs. Sumner), 385363 (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - Wellstone, Paul, 2002; 385364 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - Wen-Whe, 385365 (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - Wenner, Jan, 1974-1977; 385366 (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - Wes-Wh, 385367 (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - Wes-Wid, 385368 (Box 144, Folder 1)
    - West, Rebecca, 1953-1995; 385369 (Box 144, Folder 2-3)
    - Wh-Wie, 385370 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - Wheeler, Burton, 1959; 385371 (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - White, Byron, 1961; 385372 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - White, Morton, 1953-1992; 385373 (Box 145, Folder 4-5)
    - White, Theodore, 1966-1989; 385374 (Box 146, Folder 1)
    - Whitehead, Alfred North, 1945; 385375 (Box 146, Folder 2)
    - Wi-Wz, 385376 (Box 146, Folder 3)
    - Wic-Wis, 385377 (Box 146, Folder 4)
    - Wickremesinghe, Ranil, 2002-2003; 385378 (Box 146, Folder 5)
    - Wie-Wis, 385379 (Box 146, Folder 6)
    - Wig-Wil, 385380 (Box 147, Folder 1)
    - Win-Wy, 385381 (Box 147, Folder 2)
    - Willkie, Wendell, 1942; 385382 (Box 148, Folder 1)
    - Wintour, Anna, 385383 (Box 148, Folder 2)
    - Wintour, Charles, 1944-1994; 385384 (Box 148, Folder 3-4)
    - Wit-Z, 385385 (Box 148, Folder 5)
    - Wof-Wy, 385386 (Box 149, Folder 1)
    - Wooden, Kenneth W., 1967=1983; 385387 (Box 149, Folder 2)
    - World Book Encyclopedia, 1968-1977; 385388 (Box 149, Folder 3)
    - World Publishing Company, 1959-1965; 385389 (Box 149, Folder 4)
    - X-Z, 385390 (Box 150, Folder 1-4)
  - Subseries I.B. Subject Correspondence, 1950s-1990s; 385391; 56 boxes
    In those instances where Schlesinger corresponded with a number of individuals or organizations on the same subject, he often filed the correspondence by subject, rather than correspondent. This subseries consists of those files, alphabetized by subject. In many cases, the subject designations represent recurring elements from Schlesinger's own life and career, including correspondence related to CUNY and the Schlesinger Library at Harvard, honoring his parents. There are also files of permission requests to quote or otherwise use his writings, quote requests from authors and publishers hoping for a Schlesinger blurb on the book jacket, invitations declined by Schlesinger, and correspondence regarding his personal appearances in lectures and interviews. There are even files Schlesinger labeled Kooks, containing the less flattering and less coherent correspondence from strangers and readers.
    When the subject designations did not stem from Schlesinger's professional life, they alluded to political and world affairs. Of particular interest in that category are files on McCarthyism from the 1950s, the Democratic Party platform in 1984, and presidential campaign letters and memos from 1960. Having written about the Sacco-Vanzetti case of the 1920s, Schlesinger maintained a correspondence file about the continued study of the case in the 1950s and 1960s.
    In some cases, the subject correspondence demonstrates the intersection of personal matters with public affairs. The file on William F. Buckley, for example, contains correspondence relating to an early 1960s controversy sparked by Buckley's use of a Schlesinger quotation, intended sarcastically, as an advertisement for one of his books. Although Schlesinger and Buckley were friends, there was talk of legal action. The incident is further elucidated in Series IV.A. In the case of subject correspondence files labeled with an individual's name, the file may contain correspondence with, as well as about, that individual, as in the case of the Buckley file.
    - Addresses, 385392 (Box 151, Folder 1)
    - Anderson/Lucey Campaign 1980, 385393 (Box 151, Folder 2)
    - Appearances (arranged chronologically), 385394
      - The Great Challenge, 1959; 385395 (Box 151, Folder 3)
      - Is Democracy Obsolete?, 1961; 385396 (Box 151, Folder 4)
      - The Men in the White House, 1961; 385397 (Box 151, Folder 5)
      - Coercion or Choice?, 1961; 385398 (Box 151, Folder 6)
      - Washington Conversation, 1961; 385399 (Box 151, Folder 7)
      - Friends of JFK, 1964; 385400 (Box 151, Folder 8)
      - Meet the Press, 1965; 385401 (Box 151, Folder 9)
      - Inaugural Lecture, 1966; 385402 (Box 151, Folder 10)
      - 1966-1971, 385403 (Box 152, Folder 1)
      - Face the Nation, 1966; 385404 (Box 152, Folder 2)
      - Panorama, 1966; 385405 (Box 152, Folder 3)
      - Vietnam Negotiations Discussion, 1968; 385406 (Box 152, Folder 4)
      - Face the Nation, 1968; 385407 (Box 152, Folder 5)
      - Ten O'Clock, 1968; 385408 (Box 152, Folder 6)
      - The Birth of the Nation, 1969; 385409 (Box 152, Folder 7)
      - On Trial: The Man in the Middle, 1969; 385410 (Box 152, Folder 8)
      - The David Frost Show, 1969; 385411 (Box 152, Folder 9)
      - The Role of Intellectuals in a Democracy Undergoing Radical Change, 1970; 385412 (Box 152, Folder 10)
      - California, 1970; 385413 (Box 152, Folder 11)
      - Center Magazine meeting, 1971; 385414 (Box 152, Folder 12)
      - Open Circuit, 1972; 385415 (Box 152, Folder 13)
      - 1973, 385416 (Box 153, Folder 1)
      - Great Decisions, 1973; 385417 (Box 153, Folder 2-3)
      - 1974, 385418 (Box 153, Folder 4)
      - Always on Sunday, 1974; 385419 (Box 153, Folder 5)
      - Philip Dolce interview, CBS, 1974; 385420 (Box 153, Folder 6)
      - Tomorrow, 1974; 385421 (Box 153, Folder 7)
      - 1975, 385422 (Box 153, Folder 8)
      - The Merv Griffin Show, 1975; 385423 (Box 153, Folder 9)
      - 1976, 385424 (Box 153, Folder 10)
      - 1976-1977, 385425 (Box 153, Folder 11)
      - Tonight: Presidential Election, 1976; 385426 (Box 153, Folder 12)
      - 1977-1981, 385427 (Box 154, Folder 1-5)
      - 1982-1983, 385428 (Box 155, Folder 1-2)
      - 1990-1991, 385429 (Box 155, Folder 3)
      - 1992-1993, 385430 (Box 156, Folder 1-4)
      - 1994, 385431 (Box 157, Folder 1)
      - General, 385432 (Box 157, Folder 2)
      - Columbia Lecture Bureau, 385433 (Box 157, Folder 3-4)
      - Lecture correspondence, 385434 (Box 158, Folder 1-6)
      - Lectures and meetings, 385435 (Box 159-160)
      - Lectures and meetings, 385436 (Box 161, Folder 1-7)
      - Lecture topics, 385437 (Box 161, Folder 8)
      - Lecture miscellany, 385438 (Box 161, Folder 9)
    - Associations and organizations, 385439
      - A-K, 385440 (Box 162, Folder 1-2)
      - L-Z, 385441 (Box 163, Folder 1-5)
    - Autograph requests, 385442 (Box 164, Folder 1)
    - Awards and honors, 385443 (Box 164, Folder 2)
    - Bancroft-Emmet, Inc., 385444 (Box 164, Folder 3)
    - Book blurbs, 385445 (Box 164, Folder 4)
    - Book blurbs, 385446 (Box 165, Folder 1-4)
    - Buckley, William F., 385447 (Box 165, Folder 5)
    - Cambridge, U.K., 385448 (Box 166, Folder 1)
    - Cannon, Dr. Walter, 385449 (Box 166, Folder 2)
    - Carter-Mondale campaign, 1976; 385450 (Box 166, Folder 3)
    - Center for Inter-American Relations, 385451 (Box 166, Folder 4)
    - Central Intelligence Agency tapes, 385452 (Box 166, Folder 5)
    - Century Association, 385453 (Box 166, Folder 6)
    - Century Club, 385454 (Box 166, Folder 7)
    - Century nominations, 385455 (Box 166, Folder 8)
    - Chayefsky, Paddy, 385456 (Box 166, Folder 9)
    - Chelsea House, 385457 (Box 167, Folder 1)
    - City University of New York, 385458
      - Bildner Center for Western Hemisphere Studies, 385459 (Box 167, Folder 2)
      - Center for Advanced Studies in Education, 385460 (Box 167, Folder 3)
      - Graduate School Fellowship Fund, 385461 (Box 167, Folder 4)
      - Kibbee dinner, 385462 (Box 167, Folder 5)
      - Provost Search Committee, 385463 (Box 167, Folder 6)
      - Publications, 385464 (Box 167, Folder 7)
      - Publicity, 385465 (Box 167, Folder 8)
      - Special events, 385466 (Box 167, Folder 9)
      - General, 385467 (Box 167, Folder 10-11)
      - General, 385468 (Box 168, Folder 1-2)
    - Clark, Blair, 385469 (Box 168, Folder 3)
    - Clinton-Gore campaign, 1992; 385470 (Box 168, Folder 4)
    - Clubs, 385471 (Box 168, Folder 5)
    - Coll Campaign for Congress, 1970; 385472 (Box 169, Folder 1)
    - Communist Party USA, 385473 (Box 169, Folder 2)
    - Contracts, 385474 (Box 169, Folder 3-4)
    - Cornerstone religious quote, 385475 (Box 169, Folder 5)
    - Council of Scholars, Library of Congress, 385476 (Box 169, Folder 6)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 385477 (Box 169, Folder 7)
    - Cuba, 385478 (Box 169, Folder 8)
    - The Death of a President, 385479 (Box 170, Folder 1-4)
    - Democratic Party, 385480
      - 1970s-1980s, 385481 (Box 170, Folder 5)
      - 1984, 385482
        - Campaign, 385483 (Box 170, Folder 6)
        - Platform, 385484 (Box 170, Folder 7)
    - Endorsements, 385485 (Box 170, Folder 8)
    - Fellows, 385486 (Box 171, Folder 1)
    - Foundations, 385487 (Box 171, Folder 2)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt Library, 385488 (Box 171, Folder 3-6)
    - Franklin D. Roosevelt Library, 385489 (Box 172, Folder 1)
    - Galbraith, John Kenneth, 385490 (Box 172, Folder 2)
    - Gandhi Blurb, 1982; 385491 (Box 172, Folder 3)
    - Garland Publishing, Inc., 385492 (Box 172, Folder 4)
    - Harry S. Truman Library, 385493 (Box 172, Folder 5)
    - Houghton Mifflin, 385494 (Box 172, Folder 6)
    - Institute for Research in History, 385495 (Box 173, Folder 1)
    - Interviews, 385496
      - Yale political interview, 1962; 385497 (Box 173, Folder 2)
      - Playboy, 1966; 385498 (Box 173, Folder 3)
      - Perspectives on the American Past, 1968; 385499 (Box 173, Folder 4)
      - Murderers and Other Friendly People, 1973; 385500 (Box 173, Folder 5)
      - Der Spiegel magazine, 1974; 385501 (Box 173, Folder 6)
      - 1972-1984, 385502 (Box 173, Folder 7)
      - 1978, 385503 (Box 173, Folder 8)
      - 1979, 385504 (Box 173, Folder 9)
      - 1980, 385505 (Box 173, Folder 10)
      - 1981, 385506 (Box 173, Folder 11)
      - 1982, 385507 (Box 173, Folder 12)
      - 1983, 385508 (Box 173, Folder 13)
      - 1983-1989, 385509 (Box 173, Folder 14)
      - 1990-1991, 385510 (Box 174, Folder 1)
      - 1992-1994, 385511 (Box 174, Folder 2)
      - General, 385512 (Box 174, Folder 3)
    - Invitations, 1969-1975; 385513 (Box 175, Folder 1-2)
    - Invitations--Declined, 385514
      - 1965-1967, 385515 (Box 175, Folder 3)
      - 1967-1975, 385516 (Box 176, Folder 1-3)
      - 1976, 385517 (Box 177, Folder 1-3)
      - 1979, 385518 (Box 177, Folder 4-5)
      - 1979-1982, 385519 (Box 178, Folder 1-3)
      - 1983-1990, 385520 (Box 179, Folder 1-2)
      - 1990-1992, 385521 (Box 180, Folder 1-2)
      - General, 385522 (Box 181, Folder 1-4)
      - General, 385523 (Box 182, Folder 1-2)
    - John F. Kennedy Institute, 385524 (Box 183, Folder 1)
    - John F. Kennedy Presidential Library and Museum, 385525 (Box 183, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy, Robert F., 385526
      - Condolences, 385527 (Box 183, Folder 3)
      - General, 385528 (Box 183, Folder 4-5)
    - Kooks, 385529 (Box 184, Folder 1-2)
    - Lecturers, 385530 (Box 184, Folder 3)
    - Ledeen, Michael, 385531 (Box 184, Folder 4)
    - Liberal conference, 385532 (Box 184, Folder 5)
    - Library of America, 385533 (Box 184, Folder 6)
    - The Life and Times of Huey Long, 385534 (Box 184, Folder 7)
    - Lister, George, 385535 (Box 184, Folder 8)
    - Literary contracts, 385536 (Box 185, Folder 1)
    - Lyndon B. Johnson Library, 385537 (Box 185, Folder 2)
    - McCarthyism, 385538 (Box 185, Folder 3)
    - Memberships, 385539 (Box 185, Folder 4-5)
    - The Morgenthau Story (proposed), 385540 (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - National Archives, 385541 (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - New World Records, 385542 (Box 186, Folder 3)
    - New York bicentennial, 385543 (Box 186, Folder 4)
    - New York City mayoral election, 1981; 385544 (Box 186, Folder 5)
    - New York Public Library, 385545 (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - New York State, 385546 (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - New York Times letter, 1959; 385547 (Box 186, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper statement ads, 385548 (Box 186, Folder 9)
    - Nixon tapes case, 385549 (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Office of Strategic Services, 385550 (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Organization of American Historians, 385551 (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Organizations, 385552 (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - Pamphlets on American history, 385553 (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - Pentagon papers, 385554 (Box 187, Folder 6)
    - Permission requests, 385555
      - Atlantic Monthly, 385556 (Box 188, Folder 1)
      - Foreign Affairs, 385557 (Box 188, Folder 2-3)
      - Harpers, 385558 (Box 188, Folder 4-5)
      - The Imperial Presidency, 385559 (Box 188, Folder 6)
      - New York Review of Books, 385560 (Box 188, Folder 7)
      - New York Times Magazine, 385561 (Box 188, Folder 8)
      - Oral histories (JFK; RFK), 385562 (Box 189, Folder 1)
      - Partisan Review, 385563 (Box 189, Folder 2)
      - Robert Kennedy and His Times, 385564 (Box 189, Folder 3-4)
      - Sources of the New Deal, 385565 (Box 189, Folder 5)
      - A Thousand Days, 385566 (Box 190, Folder 1-4)
      - General, 385567 (Box 191-193)
    - Players Club, 385568 (Box 194, Folder 1)
    - Political Science Quarterly, 385569 (Box 194, Folder 2)
    - Presidential campaign, 1960; 385570 (Box 194, Folder 3)
    - Princeton University, 385571 (Box 194, Folder 4)
    - Princeton University conference, 1968; 385572 (Box 194, Folder 5)
    - Professors (Schweitzer chair), 385573 (Box 194, Folder 6)
    - Publications requested, 385574 (Box 194, Folder 7)
    - Quote requests, 385575
      - Alfred A. Knopf, 385576 (Box 195, Folder 1)
      - Atheneum Publishers, 385577 (Box 195, Folder 2)
      - Atlantic Monthly Press, 385578 (Box 195, Folder 3)
      - Charles Scribner's Sons, 385579 (Box 195, Folder 4)
      - Columbia University Press, 385580 (Box 195, Folder 5)
      - Conde Nast Traveler, 385581 (Box 195, Folder 6)
      - Doubleday and Company, 385582 (Box 195, Folder 7)
      - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 385583 (Box 195, Folder 8)
      - Harcourt Brace Jovanovich, Inc., 385584 (Box 195, Folder 9)
      - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 385585 (Box 195, Folder 10)
      - Harper & Row, 385586 (Box 195, Folder 11)
      - Houghton Mifflin, 385587 (Box 195, Folder 12)
      - Little, Brown and Company, 385588 (Box 195, Folder 13)
      - Macmillan, 385589 (Box 195, Folder 14)
      - McGraw-Hill, Inc., 385590 (Box 195, Folder 15)
      - New England Quarterly, 385591 (Box 195, Folder 16)
      - Oxford University Press, 385592 (Box 195, Folder 17)
      - Prentice-Hall, Inc., 385593 (Box 195, Folder 18)
      - Random House, 385594 (Box 195, Folder 19)
      - Simon & Schuster, 385595 (Box 195, Folder 20)
      - University of North Carolina Press, 385596 (Box 195, Folder 21)
      - Viking Press, 385597 (Box 195, Folder 22)
      - W.W. Norton and Company, 385598 (Box 195, Folder 23)
      - William Morrow and Company, 385599 (Box 195, Folder 24)
      - General, 385600 (Box 195, Folder 25)
    - Radcliffe College, 385601 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - Radio scripts, 385602 (Box 196, Folder 2)
    - Rauh, Joseph L. Jr., 385603 (Box 196, Folder 3)
    - Reading requests, 385604 (Box 196, Folder 4-5)
    - Reinhold Niebuhr Award, 385605 (Box 197, Folder 1-2)
    - Research Institute of America, 385606 (Box 197, Folder 3)
    - Robert F. Kennedy Book Awards, 385607 (Box 198, Folder 1-2)
    - Robert F. Kennedy Memorial, 385608 (Box 198, Folder 3-4)
    - Robert F. Kennedy television special, 385609 (Box 198, Folder 5)
    - Roosevelt Centennial, 385610
      - ABC, 385611 (Box 199, Folder 1)
      - Arts celebration, 385612 (Box 199, Folder 2)
      - Broadway celebration, 385613 (Box 199, Folder 3)
      - Campobello celebration, 385614 (Box 199, Folder 4)
      - Century Association, 385615 (Box 199, Folder 5)
      - Conference on Our Domestic Future, 385616 (Box 199, Folder 6)
      - Essay contest, 385617 (Box 199, Folder 7)
      - Evensong--St. John the Divine, 385618 (Box 199, Folder 8)
      - Funding, 385619 (Box 200, Folder 1)
      - Hyde Park, 385620 (Box 200, Folder 2)
      - Informative road signs, 385621 (Box 200, Folder 3)
      - Media, 385622 (Box 200, Folder 4)
      - Mid-Hudson Bridge renaming, 385623 (Box 200, Folder 5)
      - Netherlands trip, 385624 (Box 200, Folder 6)
      - New York Council for the Humanities, 385625 (Box 200, Folder 7)
      - New York State Centennial Commission, 385626 (Box 200, Folder 8)
      - Queen Beatrix visit, 385627 (Box 200, Folder 9)
      - Roosevelt Island, 385628 (Box 200, Folder 10)
      - Roosevelt special, 385629 (Box 200, Folder 11)
      - Trust for Public Land, 385630 (Box 200, Folder 12)
      - United Nations observance, 385631 (Box 200, Folder 13)
      - General, 385632 (Box 201, Folder 1-3)
    - Sacco-Vanzetti case, 385633 (Box 202, Folder 1)
    - Schlesinger Library, 385634 (Box 202, Folder 2)
    - Society of American Historians, 385635 (Box 203, Folder 1)
    - Sponsorships, 385636 (Box 203, Folder 2)
    - State Democratic Committee on National Affairs, 385637 (Box 203, Folder 3)
    - Stevenson, Adlai campaign, 385638
      - 1952, 385639 (Box 204, Folder 1-4)
      - 1952-1960, 385640 (Box 205, Folder 1-6)
    - Television, 385641 (Box 205, Folder 7)
    - Udall campaign, 1976; 385642 (Box 205, Folder 8)
    - Vietnam, 385643 (Box 205, Folder 9)
    - White House resignation, 385644 (Box 205, Folder 10)
    - General, 385645 (Box 308, Folder 1-2)
  - Subseries I.C. Chronological File, 1964-1994; 385646; 44 boxes
    This subseries consists of a monthly office file, comprised of outgoing correspondence, maintained during Schlesinger's tenure at the City University of New York. Researchers seeking a complete record of communication with a particular individual or on a given subject should check the relevant dates in the chronological office file. Other correspondence subseries do include some of Schlesinger's outgoing responses attached to letters, but this subseries is composed entirely of chronological outgoing letters.
    - 1964 Apr-Sept, 385647 (Box 206, Folder 1-6)
    - 1964 Oct-1965 Apr, 385648 (Box 207, Folder 1-7)
    - 1965 May-Dec, 385649 (Box 208, Folder 1-8)
    - 1966 Jan-May, 385650 (Box 209, Folder 1-5)
    - 1966 June-Oct, 385651 (Box 210, Folder 1-6)
    - 1966 Nov-1967 Apr, 385652 (Box 211, Folder 1-6)
    - 1967 May-Oct, 385653 (Box 212, Folder 1-6)
    - 1967 Nov-1968 Apr, 385654 (Box 213, Folder 1-6)
    - 1968 May-Oct, 385655 (Box 214, Folder 1-6)
    - 1968 Nov-1969 Mar, 385656 (Box 215, Folder 1-5)
    - 1969 Apr-Sept, 385657 (Box 216, Folder 1-6)
    - 1969 Oct-1970 Apr, 385658 (Box 217, Folder 1-7)
    - 1970 May-Dec, 385659 (Box 218, Folder 1-8)
    - 1971 Jan-July, 385660 (Box 219, Folder 1-7)
    - 1971 Aug-1972 Feb, 385661 (Box 220, Folder 1-7)
    - 1972 Mar-Sept, 385662 (Box 221, Folder 1-7)
    - 1972 Oct-1973 Apr, 385663 (Box 222, Folder 1-7)
    - 1973 May-1974 Jan, 385664 (Box 223, Folder 1-9)
    - 1974 Feb-Aug, 385665 (Box 224, Folder 1-7)
    - 1974 Sept-1975 Feb, 385666 (Box 225, Folder 1-6)
    - 1975 Mar-Oct, 385667 (Box 226, Folder 1-8)
    - 1975 Nov-1976 Aug, 385668 (Box 227, Folder 1-10)
    - 1976 Sept-1977 June, 385669 (Box 228, Folder 1-10)
    - 1977 July-1978 Mar, 385670 (Box 229, Folder 1-9)
    - 1978 Apr-Dec, 385671 (Box 230, Folder 1-9)
    - 1979 Jan-Sept, 385672 (Box 231, Folder 1-9)
    - 1979 Oct-1980 July, 385673 (Box 232, Folder 1-10)
    - 1980 Aug-1981 Mar, 385674 (Box 233, Folder 1-8)
    - 1981 Apr-Dec, 385675 (Box 234, Folder 1-9)
    - 1982 Jan-Aug, 385676 (Box 235, Folder 1-8)
    - 1982 Sept-1983 Apr, 385677 (Box 236, Folder 1-8)
    - 1983 May-1984 Jan, 385678 (Box 237, Folder 1-10)
    - 1984 Feb-Oct, 385679 (Box 238, Folder 1-9)
    - 1984 Nov-1985 Nov, 385680 (Box 239, Folder 1-13)
    - 1985 Dec-1986 Oct, 385681 (Box 240, Folder 1-11)
    - 1986 Nov-1987 Sept, 385682 (Box 241, Folder 1-11)
    - 1987 Oct-1988 Aug, 385683 (Box 242, Folder 1-11)
    - 1988 Sept-1989 June, 385684 (Box 243, Folder 1-10)
    - 1989 July-1990 April, 385685 (Box 244, Folder 1-10)
    - 1990 May-1991 April, 385686 (Box 245, Folder 1-12)
    - 1991 May-1992 Feb, 385687 (Box 246, Folder 1-10)
    - 1992 Mar-Dec, 385688 (Box 247, Folder 1-10)
    - 1993, 385689 (Box 248, Folder 1-12)
    - 1994 Jan-Aug, 385690 (Box 249, Folder 1-8)
  - Subseries I.D. Unfiled Correspondence, 1920s-2007; 385691; 14 boxes
    Schlesinger also filed correspondence chronologically, particularly in years when he did not have a full-time secretary. The limited selection of folders arranged by year indicates that this filing method was not Schlesinger's first choice, and was usually dictated by circumstance. This subseries contains those folders representing individual years of correspondence, without regard to correspondent or subject. Both incoming and outgoing letters are included. The presence of a folder in this subseries representing a given year does not preclude other correspondence from that year appearing in the Alphabetical, Subject Correspondence or Chronological File subseries.
    - 1920s-1938, 385692 (Box 250, Folder 1-5)
    - 1939-1950s, 385693 (Box 251, Folder 1-7)
    - 1950-1960, 385694 (Box 252, Folder 1-7)
    - 1960s, 385695 (Box 253, Folder 1-3)
    - 1960, 385696 (Box 253, Folder 4)
    - 1961, 385697 (Box 253, Folder 5)
    - 1964-1970, 385698 (Box 254, Folder 1-5)
    - 1970s-1990s, 385699 (Box 255, Folder 1-5)
    - 1990s, 385700 (Box 300-301)
    - 1999, 385701 (Box 302, Folder 1-2)
    - 2000-2007, 385702 (Box 303-307)
  - Subseries I.E. Publication-related, 1940s-2007; 385703; 15 boxes